<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mini-mover on Jeff Glass</title>
    <link>https://jeff.glass/tags/mini-mover/</link>
    <description>Recent content in mini-mover on Jeff Glass</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 16:37:14 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jeff.glass/tags/mini-mover/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Video: Demilight Version 0.8</title>
      <link>https://jeff.glass/backup-post/video-demilight-version-0-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 16:37:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeff.glass/backup-post/video-demilight-version-0-8/</guid>
      <description>It&#39;s been quite awhile since the mini-moving light project (now renamed The Demilight) has been written up on the blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video: Demilight Version 0.8</title>
      <link>https://jeff.glass/post/video-demilight-version-0-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 16:37:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeff.glass/post/video-demilight-version-0-8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p class=&#34;post-p&#34;&gt;It&#39;s been quite awhile since the &lt;a href=&#34;https://jeff.glass/demilight/&#34;&gt;mini-moving light project&lt;/a&gt; (now renamed The Demilight) has been written up on the blog. The project was in hiatus for a few months while dove into the technical challenges of a new job, but as the job isn&#39;t keeping quite as busy at the moment (here in early summer 2020), it&#39;s back on the workbench. I&#39;ve put together a video showcasing the current state of the project, now in &lt;strong&gt;version 0.8:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;post-p&#34;&gt;{{&amp;lt; youtube 4a-9JGK8H4I &amp;gt;}}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;post-p&#34;&gt;The video does a pretty decent job of capturing the current state of things. So what&#39;s next?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;post-p&#34;&gt;Firstly, the goofs I alluded to in the video that I consider to be &lt;em&gt;must-fix&lt;/em&gt; items before the files are ready for primetime. Theu mostly have to do with the 3D-printed parts - I adjusted the access holes and programming slots from version 0.5 to 0.8, but I didn&#39;t do a great job double-checking everything, and things don&#39;t line up very well. That&#39;ll need another few test prints and some adjustment to alleviate the all the filing that&#39;s currently necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;post-p&#34;&gt;I&#39;ve also been having some issues with mechanical assembly - I&#39;ve been using some &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2Vg1pWw&#34;&gt;M2 insert nuts&lt;/a&gt; to hold the case and case-lid together, and to secure the PCB into the case, but that doesn&#39;t seem to be a particularly good system. It&#39;s possibly my nuts and bolts are just really high-tolerance, but they&#39;re constantly cross-threading and not inserting all the way. I think a more robust solution is in order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;post-p&#34;&gt;The other main error has to do with the footprint for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.digikey.com/product-detail/en/recom-power/R-78E5.0-0.5/945-1648-5-ND/2834904&#34;&gt;5V buck-converter&lt;/a&gt; module - somehow, my pin placement is off by .2&#34; on the PCB footprint, which makes the part overlap with the attachment points for the servos unless you bend the voltage-regulator&#39;s pins over. Not insurmountable, but really annoying. That&#39;ll have to get fixed in version 0.9. Once those two most-egregious errors are corrected, though, I think the unit will be decent enough to publish as a beta version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;post-p&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;post-img&#34; height=&#34;236&#34; src=&#34;https://media.digikey.com/Photos/Recom%20Power%20Inc/MFG_R-78-e%20series.jpg&#34; width=&#34;243&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;post-image-caption&#34;&gt;It&#39;s a pretty simple part... how did I goof this up?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;post-p&#34;&gt;There are several more substantial improvements in the pipeline as well. In no particular order:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;post-p&#34;&gt;As I mention in the video, I&#39;m working on a &lt;strong&gt;miniaturized programmer interface&lt;/strong&gt; based on some little &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.digikey.com/product-detail/en/mill-max-manufacturing-corp/0985-0-15-20-71-14-11-0/ED1122-ND/3635123&#34;&gt;0.05&#34;-pitch pogo pins&lt;/a&gt;. The results, so far, have been mixed - I have been able to confirm that the interface is providing gnd/5V to the ATmega328, at least enough that its 16 MHz ceramic resonator is oscillating, but I can&#39;t seem to program the chips in-place. Further experiments will be necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;post-p&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jeff.glass/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Pogo-Pins.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter wp-image-1095 post-img&#34; height=&#34;194&#34; src=&#34;Pogo-Pins-1024x718.jpg&#34; width=&#34;276&#34;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;post-p&#34;&gt;Some iterations of the Demilight have incorporated a &lt;strong&gt;heatsink &lt;/strong&gt;to help manage the heat-output from the LED emitter chips. To be honest, I&#39;m not sure how necessary it is - I would love to set up some tests with the unit running at its full 1 Amp current and see just how hot things get. Perhaps the first test would be in free-air, then inside the case in multiple orientations. I know from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sYT-xtOL4rU&amp;amp;t=299s&#34;&gt;some tests I did on a livestream last summer&lt;/a&gt; that with enough heatsinking the LED stars can handle up to about 5 Amps, but they dump a huge amount of heat at the point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;post-p&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jeff.glass/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/heatsink.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;wp-image-1118 post-img&#34; height=&#34;256&#34; src=&#34;heatsink.png&#34; width=&#34;341&#34;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;post-image-caption&#34;&gt;If the heatsink comes back, should it still be in candy-apple red?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;post-p&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RGB &lt;/strong&gt;or &lt;strong&gt;RGBW&lt;/strong&gt; dimming capacity would be really neat - as spiffy as the pure-white versions are, there&#39;s something about color-changing light that feels like it would take this project to the next level. I would need to free up some more PCB space, and possibly move from a single-channel driver to a 3 or 4 channel driver, but finding those in the ~1A current capacity range seems a little tricky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;post-p&#34;&gt;There are also a couple of purely aesthetic things which could get bumped up to something better. I&#39;ve ordered some &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/31g67Yj&#34;&gt;1/4&#34; white wire sleeving&lt;/a&gt; to take the place of the gaff tape covering the wires that run from head to base. And I need to invest a little time dialing in my 3D printer - after &lt;a href=&#34;https://jeff.glass/2019/03/09/3d-printing-in-the-home-workshop/&#34;&gt;3.5 years of printing,&lt;/a&gt; it&#39;s starting to show its age a little bit, and a little extra tightening and lubrication wouldn&#39;t be a bad idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;post-p&#34;&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;post-p&#34;&gt;So many of my projects during quarantine have focused on building my digital communication mediums - building out this video feels very much like a continuation of that skill-building. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://jeff.glass/electronics-bash/&#34;&gt;weekly Arduino/Electronics classes&lt;/a&gt; I&#39;ve been teaching for 15 weeks now have been a serious crash course in live digital video. That learning process deserves a write-up of it&#39;s own, but if you compare the following two frames from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rRVTTIWVcXA&amp;amp;t&#34;&gt;Episode 0 (testing)&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QQYhC7xHG_s&#34;&gt;Episode 14 (Wireless Signals)&lt;/a&gt;, I think the improvements are pretty clear:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;post-p&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jeff.glass/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/EarlySnap.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;wp-image-1116 post-img&#34; height=&#34;253&#34; src=&#34;EarlySnap-300x168.png&#34; width=&#34;450&#34;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;post-img-caption&#34;&gt;Epsiode one was.... pretty rough. The audio is really crunchy too - turns out I had two microphones on (lav and webcam) and they did unkind things together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;post-p&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jeff.glass/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/latesnip.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;wp-image-1117 post-img&#34; height=&#34;253&#34; src=&#34;latesnip-300x168.png&#34; width=&#34;450&#34;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;post-img-caption&#34;&gt;We&#39;ve got things pretty well dialed in by now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;post-p&#34;&gt;It&#39;s been a joy to build some more digital video skills putting this video together, like putting together a basic script, recording a voiceover, learning the editting, effects, and color-grading processes... it&#39;s been both fascinating and time-consuming. The video definitely has some rough edges, but I&#39;m thinking of it as good-enough, and I&#39;m excited to take what I&#39;ve learned from this early creation and apply it to future videos. Much like the tiny-light itself, it&#39;s good to just make a thing, anything, a small thing, and iterate from there.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      &lt;
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>