<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cheddar on Jeff Glass</title>
    <link>https://jeff.glass/tags/cheddar/</link>
    <description>Recent content in cheddar on Jeff Glass</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 07:01:54 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jeff.glass/tags/cheddar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Homemade Cheddar Cheese</title>
      <link>https://jeff.glass/post/homemade-cheddar-cheese/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 07:01:54 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeff.glass/post/homemade-cheddar-cheese/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p class=&#34;post-p&#34;&gt;Over the past 12 months or so, I&#39;ve dipped my toes into some basic cheesemaking, including cream cheese, farmer&#39;s cheese, and ricotta. But for me, there&#39;s no better cheese than a sharp white cheddar, and with an eye toward making cheddar and some other hard cheeses, I&#39;ve built my own cheese press and my own first hard cheese.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;post-p&#34;&gt;The process I used to construct the press is very similar to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instructables.com/id/A-Simple-and-Inexpensive-Cheese-Press/&#34;&gt;this instructable&lt;/a&gt;. I used a 1x6x48&#34; Maple board from Menards as the base, and two pieces of 1x2 Poplar from an earlier project. The threaded rod, nuts, wingnuts, and washers are all 3/8&#34; hardware. I added &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.menards.com/main/tools-hardware/household-hardware/casters-furniture-hardware/furniture-slides-glides/shepherd-hardware-reg-7-8-silver-threaded-furniture-glide-4-pack/9449/p-1444442245054-c-13088.htm?tid=4069837351917205904&amp;amp;ipos=12&#34;&gt;four threaded furniture feet&lt;/a&gt; to raise the press off the countertop and allow for tilting the press slightly to allow the whey to run off. I used some butcher-block conditioner to help seal the wood before use. (Having access to a theatrical scene shop helps.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter size-large wp-image-282 post-img&#34; height=&#34;540&#34; src=&#34;IMG_5567-e1543977868759-1024x768.jpg&#34; width=&#34;720&#34;/&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;post-p&#34;&gt;My first pressed cheese is a &#34;farmhouse cheddar&#34;, made according to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.littlegreencheese.com/2011/09/farmhouse-cheddar-video-tutorial.html&#34;&gt;this recipe from Gavin Weber&lt;/a&gt;. Specifically, the ingredients I used were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;post-ul&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 Gallons (4 half-gallon containers) of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kalonasupernatural.com/our-products/organic-milk/organic-whole-milk/&#34;&gt;Kalona Whole Milk&lt;/a&gt; from our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.freshthyme.com/&#34;&gt;Fresh Thyme Market&lt;/a&gt;. While unpasteurized milk seems to be recommended for a lot of artisinal cheese making, that&#39;s hard to come by in urban Chicago, so this non-homogenized milk is the way I&#39;ve gone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 Sachet of Mesophillic Culture, purchased from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pursuitsupply.com/&#34;&gt;Pursuit Supply Co&lt;/a&gt;, a small business here in Chicago that focuses on homebrewing and distilling, cheesemaking, and film development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1/2 tsp of Liquid Vegetable Rennet, also from Pursuit Supply&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;post-ul&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This was diluted in 1/4 cup of bottled (unchlorinated) water before adding, since apparently chlorine kills the coagulating action of the rennet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1/2 tsp of Calcium Chloride (from, where else, Pursuit), also mixed with 1/4 cup bottled water. I understand this introduces more soluble calcium to the mixture and helps the curds to form.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 generous tbsp of non-iodized sea salt.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;post-p&#34;&gt;The process, as outlined by Gavin (of Little Green Workshops) is straightforward. Here is is summarized by me, with &lt;em&gt;comments&lt;/em&gt; as to how my own process went:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;post-ul&#34;&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sterilize all materials that will come into contact with the milk or cheese.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;post-ul&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I used a preparation of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pursuitsupply.com/five-star-star-san-4oz/&#34;&gt;Star-San&lt;/a&gt; mixed with water in the recommended ratio of 1:640 (1 Oz per 5 gallons). I soaked the large stirring spoon I planned to use, as well as all the measuring cups in this for a few minutes. Meanwhile, I boiled a couple quarts of water in my large stockpot to sterilize the pot itself, then wiped the lid down with the Star-San mixture.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To a large stockpot set up as a double-boiler, add the 2 gallons (8 liters) of milk.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;post-ul&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I used one of my large general-purpose pots underneath my stockpot as a double boiler, and it was remarkably stable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Heat the milk to 33C (92F)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;post-ul&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This took about 20 minutes with my double boiler setup:&lt;img alt=&#34;A large red pot of milk on a gass stove&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter size-large wp-image-283 post-img&#34; height=&#34;540&#34; src=&#34;IMG_5576-1024x768.jpg&#34; width=&#34;720&#34;/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stir in the diluted calcium chloride&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sprinkle the starter culture over the top, then stir for 1-2 minutes to incorporate&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;post-ul&#34;&gt;&lt;li&gt;Gavin&#39;s recipe calls for 1/8 tsp of culture, I simply used one small sachet.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cover, and allow the milk to ripen for 45 minutes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;post-ul&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This allows the culture to start to grow a little and the milk to begin to acidify&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I turned off the heat at this stage to allow things to maintain their temperature, but when I returned after 45 minutes, the temperature had shot up over 40C! Oops!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stir in the diluted rennet while stirring. Stir for no more than a minute as the milk with start to set.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;post-ul&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I treated myself to a very large metal spoon for this project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Check for a clean break with a clean finger&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;post-ul&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basically, stick a finger in through the top layer of curd - if it feels firm-ish, it&#39;s good to go. If it&#39;s a little soft and yogurt-y, you can cover and wait another 10 minutes or so.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cut the Curd&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;post-ul&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are some fancy curd cutters out there that look like a wire mandolin or harp, but I just used a long clean knife, run through up-down, left-right, and twice angled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Slowly heat the milk and curds to 38C (100F) over about half an hour&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;post-ul&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Even with a double boiler setup, my setup took a little modulation (higher heat, lower heat, higher heat) to not spike in temperature too fast. I took about 25 minutes to raise the temp up to 38C, sitrring continuously
&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter size-large wp-image-284 post-img&#34; height=&#34;540&#34; src=&#34;IMG_5579-1024x768.jpg&#34; width=&#34;720&#34;/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let the curds rest for 10 minutes at 38C&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;post-ul&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At this point, I should have taken the pot off the double boiler, but I figured it would help keep the milk warm. It sure did - by the time I returned 20 minutes later, the temp was up to 44C! It remains to be seen whether this will have a negative effect on the cheese.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Drain the pot into a clean cheesecloth-lined &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;b&gt;colander&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;post-ul&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I collected the Whey at this point and made a Whey Ricotta out of it. Yum!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tie up the edges of the cheesecloth and hang for an hour to drain some of the whey out&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;post-ul&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;I had a spare bit of PVC pipe leftover from my &lt;a href=&#34;https://jeff.glass/2018/07/09/a-portable-20-30-40m-vertical-antenna/&#34;&gt;multiband antenna project&lt;/a&gt;, so I set that between the backs of two chairs and set the pot underneath to catch the drippings.
&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter size-large wp-image-285 post-img&#34; height=&#34;540&#34; src=&#34;IMG_5583-1024x768.jpg&#34; width=&#34;720&#34;/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;After an hour&#39;s dripping, transfer the curds back into a pot. Break the cheese mass into walnut-sized pieces. Toss 2+ TBSP of non-iodized salt throughout.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;post-ul&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I used non-iodized sea-salt, instead of some of the products which are marketed as &#34;cheese salt.&#34; Not sure what the difference is&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Line a sanitized cheese mold with a sanitized cheese cloth. Transfer the curds to the press. Flip a corner of cheese cloth over the top of the curds, and place the follower on top.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;post-ul&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I originally tried 3D printing a mold, but I got cold feet about subjecting a 3D print to 50+ lbs of pressure overnight, fearing it would crack. I also thought it would be good to seal the PLA with polyurathane or similar before trusting it to be food-safe. So I made a simple press out of a plastic jug from Walmart with the bottom and handle cut off, and holes punched through the sides.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Press for 10 minutes at ~10 lbs.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;post-ul&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I set up my press in a low-sides baking sheet to catch the whey as it ran off, and used the threaded-feet to set the press slightly off plumb so the whey all ran off one side.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter size-large wp-image-286 post-img&#34; height=&#34;540&#34; src=&#34;IMG_5588-1024x768.jpg&#34; width=&#34;720&#34;/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remove the curds from the press and cloth, turn over, and press 10 minutes at ~25 lbs.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;post-ul&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quite a lot of whey running off at this point. Fairly cloudy, which I read is not good, but I&#39;m not sure why...
&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter size-large wp-image-287 post-img&#34; height=&#34;540&#34; src=&#34;IMG_5595-e1543978264792-1024x768.jpg&#34; width=&#34;720&#34;/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remove the curds from the press and cloth, turn over, and press for 12 hours at ~50 lbs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;post-ul&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I left the cheese to press overnight, checking it once a couple hours and tightening the springs a bit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remove the wheel of cheese from the press and cloth. Trim any bits of cheese that have popped up around the follower.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;post-ul&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leave these in the fridge for a couple days and they&#39;re basically cheese curds! So tasty!
 &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter size-large wp-image-288 post-img&#34; height=&#34;540&#34; src=&#34;IMG_5597-1024x768.jpg&#34; width=&#34;720&#34;/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Place the cheese on the counter under a bit of cheesecloth or similar to air-dry. Turn twice daily until it has a nice rind and is quite dry to the touch.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;post-ul&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I left my cheese on the counter for a little under 3 days before waxing. Possibly I should have left it longer to develop a drier rind, but we shall see when we break the thing open.
&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter size-large wp-image-289 post-img&#34; height=&#34;540&#34; src=&#34;IMG_5626-1024x768.jpg&#34; width=&#34;720&#34;/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wax or vacuum seal the cheese&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;post-ul&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After drying for a couple days, the options are to either cloth-band, wax, or vacuum seal the cheese to prevent any nasty bugs getting into the cheese.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One of Gavin&#39;s most popular videos describes Cloth-Banding the cheese, but in his final tasting of that cheese, he describes the process as too fiddly (and he did get some mold in a bit of that cheese early on). So I decided to wax the cheese instead. Pursuit was sadly out of cheese wax (soft parafin-based wax) when I stopped by, so I ordered some Beeswax from the internet to arrive the next day.
&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter size-large wp-image-290 post-img&#34; height=&#34;540&#34; src=&#34;IMG_5630-e1543978805873-1024x768.jpg&#34; width=&#34;720&#34;/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Age the cheese for 1 month to... forever?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;post-ul&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Currently, the cheddar is aging in a small mini-fridge in the basement, though with it being the early  months of winter, the fridge is turned off and is just functioning as an airtight box. I added a small dish of water and a small dish of saturated salt to raise the relative humidity to around 80-85%.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;post-p&#34;&gt;So... now we wait! I&#39;m thinking, with this being a first cheese, we&#39;ll crack it open around valentine&#39;s day (~3 months) to see how I did, then possibly re-seal it and age longer if it seems like everything&#39;s going well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;post-p&#34;&gt;One next step will be to measure the pressure that my chosen springs will create when the press is tightened down entirely. I discovered that my bathroom scale doesn&#39;t fit within the scale, so much like the instruct able suggests, I&#39;m putting together a test jig with a wider base to allow me fit the springs around the scale and make a weight gauge. I&#39;ll also need to replace the felt-bottomed feet with something that doesn&#39;t absorb whey (I threw the feet out after this batch).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;post-p&#34;&gt;Here&#39;s hoping it all turns out well!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      &lt;
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>