<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>lighting on Jeff Glass</title>
    <link>https://jeff.glass/oneofftags/lighting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in lighting on Jeff Glass</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 10:16:14 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jeff.glass/oneofftags/lighting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Lighting Control Rack Overhaul</title>
      <link>https://jeff.glass/oneoff/lightingcloset/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 10:16:14 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeff.glass/oneoff/lightingcloset/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I tasked myself with overhauling one of the lighting control closets at work. This used to house a 1995 Unison Heritage lighting controller for archetectural control, as well as an MA2 remote playback unit to control some LED fixtures and moving lights. It was all housed in an abysmal rolling rack with no connectors on it; why the rack needed to roll is beyond me. I packaged it up into a freestanding rack and replaced the Unison Heritage processor with an ETC Nomad controller for proper entertainment lighting control; installed a new network switch; and fully documented the rack&amp;rsquo;s purpose, wiring, and configuration.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      &lt;
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ahab&#39;s Harpoon</title>
      <link>https://jeff.glass/oneoff/am-hpf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeff.glass/oneoff/am-hpf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For a production of Moby Dick, the director wanted Ahab&amp;rsquo;s harpoon to glow with a heated, unearthly light just before the second intermission. I glued some warm-white LED tape just below the plexiglass tines of the harpoon, and dimmed them with an &lt;a href=&#34;https://rc4wireless.com/&#34;&gt;RC4 Wireless Dimmer&lt;/a&gt;. The power came from three 18650 lithium ion batteries.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      &lt;
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lighting XKeys</title>
      <link>https://jeff.glass/oneoff/ion-xkeys/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeff.glass/oneoff/ion-xkeys/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A very popular lighting controller in the theatrical nonprofit world is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.etcconnect.com/Products/Consoles/Eos-Family/Ion/Features.aspx&#34;&gt;ETC Ion&lt;/a&gt;, which was my primary controller two lighting jobs ago now. I found that a 16-key set of &lt;a href=&#34;https://xkeys.com/xk16.html&#34;&gt;Programming XKeys&lt;/a&gt; fits just right alongside the control console. The keys act like a USB keyboard to run pre-programmed macros on the console to replicate common or longwinded sequences of keystrokes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      &lt;
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>