<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>parks-on-the-air on Jeff Glass</title>
    <link>https://jeff.glass/tags/parks-on-the-air/</link>
    <description>Recent content in parks-on-the-air on Jeff Glass</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 20:18:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jeff.glass/tags/parks-on-the-air/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>First Parks on the Air Activation - K-4160, Volo Bog</title>
      <link>https://jeff.glass/post/first-parks-on-the-air-activation-k-4160-volo-bog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 20:18:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeff.glass/post/first-parks-on-the-air-activation-k-4160-volo-bog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p class=&#34;post-p&#34;&gt;I mentioned in my &lt;a href=&#34;https://jeff.glass/2021/07/06/ham-radio-field-day-2021-storms-and-stations/&#34;&gt;Field Day post&lt;/a&gt; from a few weeks ago that I was hoping to get out to a &lt;a href=&#34;https://parksontheair.com/&#34;&gt;Parks on the Air&lt;/a&gt; activation soon, and this past Saturday, I made it happen!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;post-p&#34;&gt;Parks on the Air is an international program inspired by the &lt;a href=&#34;https://npota.arrl.org/&#34;&gt;ARRL&#39;s 2016 National Parks on the Air event&lt;/a&gt;. While that program ended at the beginning of 2017, a group of invested amateurs set about booting up an independent, ongoing program in the style of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sota.org.uk/&#34;&gt;Summits on the Air&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.iota-world.org/&#34;&gt;Islands on the Air&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://wwff.co/&#34;&gt;World Wide Flora and Fauna&lt;/a&gt;, etc. The program engages two (overlapping) sets of radio operators: &#39;Activators&#39; who set up portable, temporary operations in state and national parks and wildlands, and &#39;Hunters&#39; who seek them out on the air from more permanent setups. Of course, you can make &#39;park to park&#39; contacts and be a hunter and an activator at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;post-p&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Parks on the Air | POTA | Parks program for amateur radio.&#34; class=&#34;w-1/4 aligncenter post-img&#34; src=&#34;http://parksontheair.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/cropped-thumbnail_Graphic4.jpg&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;post-p&#34;&gt;The draw of this for me is, as I alluded to in the Field Day post - I love the energy of being in the middle of a pile-up. Even if these contacts have a more lighthearted and friendly feel than a rapid fire contest, being a desirable contact on the air is a really jam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;post-p&#34;&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;post-p&#34;&gt;After attending the South Milwaukee Amateur Radio Club&#39;s swapmeet in the morning, I headed back south to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www2.illinois.gov/dnr/Parks/Pages/VoloBog.aspx&#34;&gt;Volo Bog State Natural Area&lt;/a&gt;, a wilderness preserve in Northern Illinois.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;post-p&#34;&gt;The park surrounds a large natural mashland, with many miles of a loop hiking path, scenic overlooks and, importantly for radio operations, a picnic area. I did some scouting on Google Maps ahead of time, and guessed that the picnic tables would be far enough apart that I could find a quiet corner to operate in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;post-p&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jeff.glass/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/volo.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter wp-image-3747 post-img&#34; height=&#34;436&#34; src=&#34;volo.png&#34; width=&#34;531&#34;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;post-p&#34;&gt;And indeed, apart from a few hikers and what looked like a field-trip just departing, the park was pretty quiet. I found a nice picnic table in the shade next to the marsh to set myself up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;post-p&#34;&gt;My setup for the day was somewhat more powerful than my Field day setup, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;pl-8 post-ul&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.yaesu.com/indexVS.cfm?cmd=DisplayProducts&amp;amp;ProdCatID=102&amp;amp;encProdID=DF4DB262968932E999EAF928B5B6A1A7&amp;amp;DivisionID=65&amp;amp;isArchived=0&#34;&gt;Yaesu FT-891&lt;/a&gt; running ~70W SSB on 20m and 15m, with the included microphone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wolfrivercoils.com/products.html&#34;&gt;Wolf River Coils TIA Mini-Mega antenna&lt;/a&gt; - in retrospect, I didn&#39;t need to install the base-loading coil, since the 17&#39; whip is full size on 15m and 20m.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No tuner, but I did bring my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eham.net/reviews/view-product?id=234&#34;&gt;Autek RF-1&lt;/a&gt; to make sure the antenna was adjusted correctly for each band.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bioennopower.com/collections/12v-series-lifepo4-batteries/products/copy-of-12v-12ah-lfp-battery-pvc-blf-1212w&#34;&gt; Bioenno 12v, 12Ah LiFePO battery.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A little powerpole &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2U5npWK&#34;&gt;Power Analyzer&lt;/a&gt; to track power usage from the battery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My classic Hamkey iambic paddle on its little plastic base&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A paper logbook&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;post-p&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;post-p&#34;&gt;Oh what fun was had! I made 98 QSOs in roughly two hours of operating - all but 4 of which were on 20m, the last few on 15m. The bands were all over the place. I had wild swings of propagation into the eastern seaboard and the Southeast; at one point, I had five consecutive contacts from the same corner of Northwest Georgia. But I also reached some ears out in the Southwest, and even a handful of stations out in Oregon and Washington. I also made 8 (I believe) Park to Park contacts with other operators out the in wild.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;post-p&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jeff.glass/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/pota.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter size-large wp-image-3746 post-img&#34; height=&#34;414&#34; src=&#34;pota-1024x589.png&#34; width=&#34;720&#34;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;post-p&#34;&gt;All in all, a tremendous day of fun and excitement, and I&#39;m looking forward to getting back on the air in a park soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;post-p&#34;&gt;73&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      &lt;
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>