<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Jeff Glass</title>
    <link>http://example.org/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Jeff Glass</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 20:18:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>First Parks on the Air Activation - K-4160, Volo Bog</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/first-parks-on-the-air-activation-k-4160-volo-bog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 20:18:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/first-parks-on-the-air-activation-k-4160-volo-bog/</guid>
      <description>I mentioned in my Field Day post from a few weeks ago that I was hoping to get out to a Parks on the Air activation soon, and this past Saturday, I made it happen!
Parks on the Air is an international program inspired by the ARRL&#39;s 2016 National Parks on the Air event. While that program ended at the beginning of 2017, a group of invested amateurs set about booting up an independent, ongoing program in the style of Summits on the Air, Islands on the Air, World Wide Flora and Fauna, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ham Radio Field Day 2021 - Storms and Stations</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/ham-radio-field-day-2021-storms-and-stations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 01:22:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/ham-radio-field-day-2021-storms-and-stations/</guid>
      <description>This post is cross-posted to my Ham Radio specific blog, kk9jef.wordpress.com
Despite sunburns, shattered plastic, and a literal tornado warning, sunburns, I had a great time at Field Day 2021 this year.
My intention had been to head out to the northern Chicago suburbs on Saturday morning for some testing of the setup. My wife and I had purchased an annual pass to the Lake County dog parks in anticipation of the Fourth of July weekend, and our plan had been to drop her (and Winnifred, a very good dog) at one of these parks, go around the corner to a quieter, non-dog-filled local park, setup and operate for an hour and change, then pick the two of them up and head home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advent of Code 2020: Day 2-9</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/advent-of-code-2020-day-2-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 16:17:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/advent-of-code-2020-day-2-9/</guid>
      <description>.js&#34;--Code for all days is on GitHub
Day 2Nothing terribly fancy going on with the day 2 challenge - essentially, reading in a text file and doing operations on strings. After developing the ability to split the input lines and validate them in part one, part 2 throws a curveball by changing up how the lines should be validated. I refactored my &#34;isValidLine&#34; code to take a validation function as one of its arguments, since the parsing/splitting of the line is the same for both parts 1 and 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advent of Code 2020: Day 1</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/advent-of-code-2020-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 16:58:57 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/advent-of-code-2020-day-1/</guid>
      <description>I know in my introductory post I said I wasn&#39;t going to post something every day, and I meant it! But I ended up with a little extra time on my hands today and this casual summary has turned into an actual post... I&#39;m going to have to think about how I categorize these posts so anyone who stumbled across my blog isn&#39;t wading through five pages of Advent of Code writeups before getting to tiny moving lights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advent of Code 2020</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/advent-of-code-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 19:31:37 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/advent-of-code-2020/</guid>
      <description>Last winter, I participated in the annual Advent of Code Challenge, a website which offers small (but not necessarily easy) programming challenges every day from December 1 through 25. It turned out to be a great way to get exposed to different corners of development in my language of choice (Python), and with a little more time on my hands this Winter, I&#39;m excited to dive into it again.
The challenges are all written in a non-programming-language-specific way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demilight-version 0.9.1</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/demilight-v-0-9-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 17:52:04 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/demilight-v-0-9-1/</guid>
      <description>The Demilight (miniature moving light) project has been slowed down in the past few months, mostly by good things. Namely, my return to my fulltime job and other interesting technical nerdery. But the project soldiers on!
I made a video detailing the trials and tribulations of getting version 0.9.1 built, which you can watch below (embedded) or over on YouTube.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Livestream a (Technology Focused) Class</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/how-to-livestream-a-technology-focused-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 17:37:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/how-to-livestream-a-technology-focused-class/</guid>
      <description>In BC times (Before Covid), I had often dreamed of setting up a semi-regular gathering with some nerd friends to make things. We&#39;d all sit around, drink beer, eat trail mix, and bash things together with Arduinos and Raspberry Pis and servos and LEDs and what have you. And then March 2020 rolled around - getting together in person was suddenly passé, but with my day job sending us home for &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demilight Version 0.8.1</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/demilight-version-0-8-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 03:01:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/demilight-version-0-8-1/</guid>
      <description>The newest round of Demilight PCBs and 3D-Prints have taken shape as version 0.8.1. Here&#39;s a brief video overview of the current state of thing:
  
The biggest change, as I mention in the video, is that I tried out JLCPCB&#39;s surface mount parts assembly service for the firs time. Overall, I&#39;m very satisfied, and I&#39;m delighted to have such a useful shortcut for assembly of these PCBs. The version 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reverse Engineering and Replacing an Industrial 7-Segment Display – Part 2, Investigation</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/reverse-engineering-and-replacing-an-industrial-7-segment-display-part-2-investigation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 20:51:45 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/reverse-engineering-and-replacing-an-industrial-7-segment-display-part-2-investigation/</guid>
      <description>This is Part 2 of an N-part series. See also [Part 1].
In part one of this series, we began the process of developing a replacement for the LASCAR EM-4-LED 4-digit industrial 7 segment display. To recap: we mined the display&#39;s datasheet for all it we could, then opened up the device to reveal its component parts and continued to dig into their datasheets until we had a reasonably complete view of the device&#39;s functions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
