<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Jeff Glass</title>
    <link>http://example.org/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Jeff Glass</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 20:18:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>First Parks on the Air Activation - K-4160, Volo Bog</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/first-parks-on-the-air-activation-k-4160-volo-bog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 20:18:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/first-parks-on-the-air-activation-k-4160-volo-bog/</guid>
      <description>I mentioned in my Field Day post from a few weeks ago that I was hoping to get out to a Parks on the Air activation soon, and this past Saturday, I made it happen!
Parks on the Air is an international program inspired by the ARRL&#39;s 2016 National Parks on the Air event. While that program ended at the beginning of 2017, a group of invested amateurs set about booting up an independent, ongoing program in the style of Summits on the Air, Islands on the Air, World Wide Flora and Fauna, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ham Radio Field Day 2021 - Storms and Stations</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/ham-radio-field-day-2021-storms-and-stations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 01:22:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/ham-radio-field-day-2021-storms-and-stations/</guid>
      <description>This post is cross-posted to my Ham Radio specific blog, kk9jef.wordpress.com
Despite sunburns, shattered plastic, and a literal tornado warning, sunburns, I had a great time at Field Day 2021 this year.
My intention had been to head out to the northern Chicago suburbs on Saturday morning for some testing of the setup. My wife and I had purchased an annual pass to the Lake County dog parks in anticipation of the Fourth of July weekend, and our plan had been to drop her (and Winnifred, a very good dog) at one of these parks, go around the corner to a quieter, non-dog-filled local park, setup and operate for an hour and change, then pick the two of them up and head home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advent of Code 2020: Day 2-9</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/advent-of-code-2020-day-2-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 16:17:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/advent-of-code-2020-day-2-9/</guid>
      <description>.js&#34;--Code for all days is on GitHub
Day 2Nothing terribly fancy going on with the day 2 challenge - essentially, reading in a text file and doing operations on strings. After developing the ability to split the input lines and validate them in part one, part 2 throws a curveball by changing up how the lines should be validated. I refactored my &#34;isValidLine&#34; code to take a validation function as one of its arguments, since the parsing/splitting of the line is the same for both parts 1 and 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advent of Code 2020: Day 1</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/advent-of-code-2020-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 16:58:57 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/advent-of-code-2020-day-1/</guid>
      <description>I know in my introductory post I said I wasn&#39;t going to post something every day, and I meant it! But I ended up with a little extra time on my hands today and this casual summary has turned into an actual post... I&#39;m going to have to think about how I categorize these posts so anyone who stumbled across my blog isn&#39;t wading through five pages of Advent of Code writeups before getting to tiny moving lights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advent of Code 2020</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/advent-of-code-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 19:31:37 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/advent-of-code-2020/</guid>
      <description>Last winter, I participated in the annual Advent of Code Challenge, a website which offers small (but not necessarily easy) programming challenges every day from December 1 through 25. It turned out to be a great way to get exposed to different corners of development in my language of choice (Python), and with a little more time on my hands this Winter, I&#39;m excited to dive into it again.
The challenges are all written in a non-programming-language-specific way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demilight-version 0.9.1</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/demilight-v-0-9-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 17:52:04 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/demilight-v-0-9-1/</guid>
      <description>The Demilight (miniature moving light) project has been slowed down in the past few months, mostly by good things. Namely, my return to my fulltime job and other interesting technical nerdery. But the project soldiers on!
I made a video detailing the trials and tribulations of getting version 0.9.1 built, which you can watch below (embedded) or over on YouTube.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Livestream a (Technology Focused) Class</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/how-to-livestream-a-technology-focused-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 17:37:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/how-to-livestream-a-technology-focused-class/</guid>
      <description>In BC times (Before Covid), I had often dreamed of setting up a semi-regular gathering with some nerd friends to make things. We&#39;d all sit around, drink beer, eat trail mix, and bash things together with Arduinos and Raspberry Pis and servos and LEDs and what have you. And then March 2020 rolled around - getting together in person was suddenly passé, but with my day job sending us home for &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demilight Version 0.8.1</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/demilight-version-0-8-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 03:01:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/demilight-version-0-8-1/</guid>
      <description>The newest round of Demilight PCBs and 3D-Prints have taken shape as version 0.8.1. Here&#39;s a brief video overview of the current state of thing:
  
The biggest change, as I mention in the video, is that I tried out JLCPCB&#39;s surface mount parts assembly service for the firs time. Overall, I&#39;m very satisfied, and I&#39;m delighted to have such a useful shortcut for assembly of these PCBs. The version 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reverse Engineering and Replacing an Industrial 7-Segment Display – Part 2, Investigation</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/reverse-engineering-and-replacing-an-industrial-7-segment-display-part-2-investigation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 20:51:45 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/reverse-engineering-and-replacing-an-industrial-7-segment-display-part-2-investigation/</guid>
      <description>This is Part 2 of an N-part series. See also [Part 1].
In part one of this series, we began the process of developing a replacement for the LASCAR EM-4-LED 4-digit industrial 7 segment display. To recap: we mined the display&#39;s datasheet for all it we could, then opened up the device to reveal its component parts and continued to dig into their datasheets until we had a reasonably complete view of the device&#39;s functions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PICO-8: Orbit</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/pico-8-orbit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 16:50:44 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/pico-8-orbit/</guid>
      <description>Over the past couple weeks, as a way to stretch my programming legs and play around with a new system, I&#39;ve been writing a little demo in the 8-bit retro video game environment called PICO-8. Since I think I&#39;m drifting away from this project now, I figured I might as well post my progress here: a &#34;game&#34; demo called Orbit that instantiates a number of objects moving in an elliptical orbit around a central planet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video: Demilight Version 0.8</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/video-demilight-version-0-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 16:37:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/video-demilight-version-0-8/</guid>
      <description>It&#39;s been quite awhile since the mini-moving light project (now renamed The Demilight) has been written up on the blog. The project was in hiatus for a few months while dove into the technical challenges of a new job, but as the job isn&#39;t keeping quite as busy at the moment (here in early summer 2020), it&#39;s back on the workbench. I&#39;ve put together a video showcasing the current state of the project, now in version 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stream - Electrics and Electronics Bash - Arduino #1</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/stream-electrics-and-electronics-bash-arduino-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 18:27:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/stream-electrics-and-electronics-bash-arduino-1/</guid>
      <description>This Sunday evening, March 22nd 2020 at 7pm Central time, I&#39;ll be hosting a livestreaming Introduction to Arduino over on YouTube!
We&#39;ll start from scratch installing the Arduino IDE software, then moving on to programming fundamentals, wiring to the Arduino and using a breadboard, and more. We should cover enough ground to be useful to absolute beginners and pro&#39;s alike.
Grab a cold one and come join me live as we make stuff and learn things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geared Nameplate</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/geared-nameplate/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2020 20:40:50 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/geared-nameplate/</guid>
      <description>A quickie today - over the weekend, I decided that my workshop at work needed a nameplate outside the door, to make it a little easier for folks to find me. So I put together this design in Fusion 360, and printed it in black and white PLA+. (The &#34;grey&#34; of the gears is a single later of white PLA on top of black gears).

The gears have 8, 9, 10, 12, 14, and 16 teeth, and are symmetrical left/right.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reverse Engineering and Replacing an Industrial 7-Segment Display - Part 1, Research</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/reverse-engineering-and-replacing-an-industrial-7-segment-display-part-1-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2020 00:05:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/reverse-engineering-and-replacing-an-industrial-7-segment-display-part-1-research/</guid>
      <description>Building one-off hardware is one part inventing, one part dissecting, one part scrounging. When we try to hit that magic mixture of good, fast, and cheap, so often we must rely on prebuilt modules - if we&#39;re trying to build a widget that gets us from zero to 100, it may only be financially/temporarily/technologically reasonable if someone already makes a module that gets us from 0 to 80. Utilizing economies of scale of already-developed parts can bring a one-off project from the realm of fantasy into feasibility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up an Electronics Lab - Tools</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/setting-up-an-electronics-lab-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 23:54:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/setting-up-an-electronics-lab-tools/</guid>
      <description>Between 10 years working in stage lighting, live video, and theatrical special effects; three moves and two home workbench-overhauls; and my new-this-month position as an Exhibit Engineer at a major Midwest science museum, I&#39;ve planned and kitted-out many electronics workbenches over the years. For those interested in getting involved in hobby or professional electronics work, I&#39;ve compiled the tools I think are most useful when building up a workspace for electronics construction and troubleshooting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Closet Door Locker</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/closet-door-locker/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2019 20:54:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/closet-door-locker/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I install a new closet door in our front entrance hall, and discovered a problem which I then solved with 3D Printing. The door is a standard bi-fold type, with pins in the top and bottom of one side for rotation, a central vertical hinge, and a track along the top to keep the far side in alignment.
The problem was - with the volume of coats we need to survive a the winter on the ice planet Hoth (Chicago) and the positioning of the hanger rail, the coats push the door out and prevent it from staying fulling closed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ETC Console Output Counts</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/etc-console-output-counts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 19:26:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/etc-console-output-counts/</guid>
      <description>What follows is a list of output-counts for ETC Eos Family consoles. Because I&#39;m always needing to reference this information, and I want to be lazy when I need to find it. So, without further ado, here&#39;s the current output capacity for different ETC consoles, as of July 24, 2019:.tg {border-collapse:collapse;border-spacing:0;border-color:#ccc;} .tg td{font-family:Arial, sans-serif;font-size:14px;padding:10px 5px;border-style:solid;border-width:1px;overflow:hidden;word-break:normal;border-color:#ccc;color:#333;background-color:#fff;} .tg th{font-family:Arial, sans-serif;font-size:14px;font-weight:normal;padding:10px 5px;border-style:solid;border-width:1px;overflow:hidden;word-break:normal;border-color:#ccc;color:#333;background-color:#f0f0f0;} .tg .tg-buh4{background-color:#f9f9f9;text-align:left;vertical-align:top} .tg .tg-0pky{border-color:inherit;text-align:left;vertical-align:top} .tg .tg-btxf{background-color:#f9f9f9;border-color:inherit;text-align:left;vertical-align:top} .tg .tg-0lax{text-align:left;vertical-align:top} 
ConsoleVariantBase Output CountUnlocked Output CountLegacy Consoles Upgraded to 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arduino DMX &#39;Light Board&#39;, Mini Moving Light Hanging Hardware</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/arduino-dmx-light-board-mini-moving-light-hanging-hardware/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2019 03:15:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/arduino-dmx-light-board-mini-moving-light-hanging-hardware/</guid>
      <description>Over the past week, I got to the point with the mini moving light that I needed some way to consistently pump DMX into my prototypes to test their functionality. Thankfully, the first set of PCBs I built for this project function as both DMX receivers and transmitters, so whipping together a basic DMX controller only took about 20 minutes.
So here it is: my tiny DMX controlled &#34;light board&#34;:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DMX Mini Moving Light First Assembly - Live Stream</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/dmx-mini-moving-light-first-assembly-live-stream/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 01:47:48 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/dmx-mini-moving-light-first-assembly-live-stream/</guid>
      <description>With the shell 3D-printed and the PCB assembled, I went ahead and put together my first &#34;completed&#34; mini-moving light, live on camera:
  It went fairly well - everything mostly worked and nothing caught fire!
There are a few mechanical and electrical takeaways for the next version, including:
Mechanical:Ennlarge the hole for LED wires in the lower caseMake a brief instruction manual for myself of what needs to be assembled/installed/solder in what orderHole for program/enable switch accessFix tolerances on the tilt-servo/yoke interfaceLengthen the body to accommodate a heatsink for the LED starFigure out mounting/hanging hardwareElectrical:Increase the spacing between Pan and Tilt Servo padsOrder higher-current 5V regulator (1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DMX Mini Moving Light Shield V0.3</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/dmx-mini-moving-light-shield-v0.3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 03:23:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/dmx-mini-moving-light-shield-v0.3/</guid>
      <description>As I hinted to in my original post about the Arduino Pro Mini DMX Shield, and then talked some about in my PCB Assembly Livestream, the latest version of my DMX shield is geared toward driving in miniature moving light. This means that, in addition to being able to receive DMX, the Arduino driving the device will need to be able to drive a couple of servos and dim a relatively high power LED.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DMX Mini Mover Shield PCB Assembly Stream</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/dmx-mini-mover-shield-pcb-assembly-stream/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 14:44:40 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/dmx-mini-mover-shield-pcb-assembly-stream/</guid>
      <description>Last night, as I started to assemble V0.3 of my DMX Mini-Mover Shield, I thought it might be fun to switch on my webcam and stream the assembly live to the World Wide Web. What follows is about 80 minutes of unstructured benchwork, chatting about DMX, sACN, and circuitry, and a first test of the new LED dimming circuit. Will it light up, or will it go boom? Watch the video to find out:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3D Printing in the Home Workshop</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/3d-printing-in-the-home-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 17:09:21 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/3d-printing-in-the-home-workshop/</guid>
      <description>With the bulk of the shelving and organization overhaul complete as of last week, I&#39;ve spent the last week starting to personalize my home workshop space, mostly using my 3D Printer. This is definitely a situation of &#34;when your favorite tool is a hammer, everything looks like a nail.&#34; And the 3D printer is an awfully nice hammer...
There are some things that 3D printed plastic parts are perfect for, including:  Brackets to attach/connect unusual shapes  Containers/guides for specific materials and tools  Stands and supports for lightweight goods But of course, there are some properties that 3D printed thermoplastics are always going to be underachievers in, like:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home Office Overhaul</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/home-office-overhaul/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 16:05:45 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/home-office-overhaul/</guid>
      <description>You may get the impression from this blog that I like to dabble in a lot of different projects. You&#39;re not wrong - I love trying new hobbies, new technologies, new recipies, new stuff. But one of the issues is that the old projects (and the pieces and tools that come with them) tend to pile up in my workspace. So with a kindly nudge from my partner, I decided it was time to overhaul my home office setup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lighting Control Protocols and Standards</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/lighting-control-protocols-and-standards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 16:18:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/lighting-control-protocols-and-standards/</guid>
      <description>The world of stage lighting uses a variety of communication protocols to link control devices (computers, light boards, houselighting systems) to endpoint devices (lights, dimmers, effects). These run the gamut from basic analog control through legacy serial protocols to modern packetized, ethernet-based protocols.
The specifications of many of the most widely-adopted protocols are managed by the Entertainment Services and Technology Association through their Technical Standards Program. Confusing matters slightly, these protocols are sometimes referred to by their ESTA standards numbers, often interchangeably with the common names.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CDV-720 3A High Range Radiation Meter</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/cdv-720-3a-high-range-radiation-meter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 04:27:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/cdv-720-3a-high-range-radiation-meter/</guid>
      <description>This post is cross-posted to my ham-radio specific blog, kk9jef.wordpress.com
I went to the WCRA Hamfest in St. Charles this weekend in search of test gear (I had been fortunate to find a working Heathkit IM-2420 Frequency Counter there a couple years ago). I didn&#39;t come away with anything of that sort, but I did scoop up this yellow beauty:
This beaut is a CDV-720 3A High Range Radiation Meter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homemade Cheddar Cheese</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/homemade-cheddar-cheese/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 07:01:54 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/homemade-cheddar-cheese/</guid>
      <description>Over the past 12 months or so, I&#39;ve dipped my toes into some basic cheesemaking, including cream cheese, farmer&#39;s cheese, and ricotta. But for me, there&#39;s no better cheese than a sharp white cheddar, and with an eye toward making cheddar and some other hard cheeses, I&#39;ve built my own cheese press and my own first hard cheese.
The process I used to construct the press is very similar to this instructable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>150 Switches</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/150-switches/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 03:52:29 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/150-switches/</guid>
      <description>I got lots of wonderful little gifties for my recent birthday, but one of the most out-there was a bag of 150 Assorted Rocker Slide and Toggle switches from Jameco. It&#39;s literally a 2 pound scoop of switches in a plastic bag, sealed and mailed. Thanks Mom and Dad!
I spent a good 10 minutes sorting it out - here&#39;s all that squinched into 45 seconds:
  
So, what do you get in a two pound sack of switches?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>50W QRP Amplifier - 3D Printed Case Design and Livestream</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/50w-qrp-amplifier-3d-printed-case-design-and-livestream/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 19:02:19 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/50w-qrp-amplifier-3d-printed-case-design-and-livestream/</guid>
      <description>With the 50W QRP amplifier project coming along nicely, I felt it was time to start thinking about a reproducible case for the project. And for custom, reproducible cases, 3D printing is my current tool of choice.
I ended up designing the case on a YouTube Livestream on Saturday night, to which a few great colleagues stopped by to ask questions and offer advice. The full video is below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>50W QRP Amplifier - Schematic, PCB Ver 1</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/50w-qrp-amplifier-schematic-pcb-ver-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Aug 2018 20:56:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/50w-qrp-amplifier-schematic-pcb-ver-1/</guid>
      <description>The 5W-to-50W QRP HF Amplifier project is rolling along nicely - I received the first PCB draft in the male this week and am 90% of the way through assembling it, with only heatsink-placement left to sort out.
I&#39;ve made a couple of additions to the schematic since the original layout, including a relay-activated indicator (R27 and its LED) and an RF-output sensing LED (from C14 to its associated LED to ground) along the the lines of VK3YE&#39;s recent project.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
