<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ham-radio on Jeff Glass</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/ham-radio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ham-radio on Jeff Glass</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 20:18:25 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/ham-radio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Virgin Receiver</title>
      <link>http://example.org/oneoff/virgin-receiver/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 20:18:25 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/oneoff/virgin-receiver/</guid>
      <description>One of the earliest homebrew ham radio transceivers I built was a direct-conversion receiver for the 40m band. I packaged it in the aluminum box of the &amp;ldquo;Lose Your Virginity&amp;rdquo; kit I had been given as a gag gift by some friends, and therefore christened it &amp;ldquo;The Virgin Receiver.&amp;rdquo;
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Estate Sale (Oct &#39;21)</title>
      <link>http://example.org/oneoff/estatesale/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 20:56:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/oneoff/estatesale/</guid>
      <description>In October 2021, I attended the estate sale of a recently-passed Ham Radio operator (&amp;ldquo;silent key&amp;rdquo;). He had collected a wild variety of goodies over the years, a few of which caught my eye. I didn&amp;rsquo;t bring home nearly all of these, but I thought they were worth capturing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Parks on the Air Activation - K-4160, Volo Bog</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/first-parks-on-the-air-activation-k-4160-volo-bog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 20:18:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/first-parks-on-the-air-activation-k-4160-volo-bog/</guid>
      <description>I mentioned in my Field Day post from a few weeks ago that I was hoping to get out to a Parks on the Air activation soon, and this past Saturday, I made it happen!
Parks on the Air is an international program inspired by the ARRL&#39;s 2016 National Parks on the Air event. While that program ended at the beginning of 2017, a group of invested amateurs set about booting up an independent, ongoing program in the style of Summits on the Air, Islands on the Air, World Wide Flora and Fauna, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ham Radio Field Day 2021 - Storms and Stations</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/ham-radio-field-day-2021-storms-and-stations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 01:22:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/ham-radio-field-day-2021-storms-and-stations/</guid>
      <description>This post is cross-posted to my Ham Radio specific blog, kk9jef.wordpress.com
Despite sunburns, shattered plastic, and a literal tornado warning, sunburns, I had a great time at Field Day 2021 this year.
My intention had been to head out to the northern Chicago suburbs on Saturday morning for some testing of the setup. My wife and I had purchased an annual pass to the Lake County dog parks in anticipation of the Fourth of July weekend, and our plan had been to drop her (and Winnifred, a very good dog) at one of these parks, go around the corner to a quieter, non-dog-filled local park, setup and operate for an hour and change, then pick the two of them up and head home.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
