<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>3d-printing on Jeff Glass</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/3d-printing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 3d-printing on Jeff Glass</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 10:16:14 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/3d-printing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>KVM Stand</title>
      <link>http://example.org/oneoff/kvm-stand/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 10:16:14 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/oneoff/kvm-stand/</guid>
      <description>My work often involves switching between several computers - a laptop, a beefier desktop, an &amp;lsquo;IT Sanctioned&amp;rsquo; clean machine with access to the work network, and a temporary line to whatever computer&amp;rsquo;s on the workbench. To improve the ergonomics of using the KVM switch, I designed and 3D-printed a small stand to hold the switch controls, then labelled it using an old embossing Dymo label maker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DIN Rail DAC Mount</title>
      <link>http://example.org/oneoff/din_rail_adc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 12:47:53 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/oneoff/din_rail_adc/</guid>
      <description>One of our retrofit projects at work required using four small DAC boards to converet 0-5V PWM into true 0-10V analog voltage. I designed and printed some small snap-on DIN rail mounts for these to cleanly mount them in their enclosure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Airflow Passthrough</title>
      <link>http://example.org/oneoff/airpassthrough/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2021 13:17:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/oneoff/airpassthrough/</guid>
      <description>The airflow situation is often very stuffy, especially in the summer months. The adjacent workroom has abundant AC, enough to keep a full room full of incandescent fixtures at bay. I punched through the wall (with permission) and mounted the fan from an old server rack over the top. I added grills to both sides to prevent knicked fingers. I designed and 3d-printed a cover with locking knurled handles to cover the hole when I&amp;rsquo;m not present or the temperature is fine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Votive Fence Hooks</title>
      <link>http://example.org/oneoff/weddinghooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 20:56:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/oneoff/weddinghooks/</guid>
      <description>I had very little to do with this one, but just think it&amp;rsquo;s neat - a friend was hosting a small backyard wedding, and while he had designed a 3D-printed hook to hold votive candles on a fence, his printer was down. I spun up around 30 hooks that week, and the wedding turned out beautiful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demilight-version 0.9.1</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/demilight-v-0-9-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 17:52:04 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/demilight-v-0-9-1/</guid>
      <description>The Demilight (miniature moving light) project has been slowed down in the past few months, mostly by good things. Namely, my return to my fulltime job and other interesting technical nerdery. But the project soldiers on!
I made a video detailing the trials and tribulations of getting version 0.9.1 built, which you can watch below (embedded) or over on YouTube.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
