<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Oneoffs on Jeff Glass</title>
    <link>http://example.org/oneoff/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Oneoffs on Jeff Glass</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 20:18:25 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/oneoff/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Virgin Receiver</title>
      <link>http://example.org/oneoff/virgin-receiver/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 20:18:25 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/oneoff/virgin-receiver/</guid>
      <description>One of the earliest homebrew ham radio transceivers I built was a direct-conversion receiver for the 40m band. I packaged it in the aluminum box of the &amp;ldquo;Lose Your Virginity&amp;rdquo; kit I had been given as a gag gift by some friends, and therefore christened it &amp;ldquo;The Virgin Receiver.&amp;rdquo;
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DIN Rail DAC Mount</title>
      <link>http://example.org/oneoff/din_rail_adc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 12:47:53 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/oneoff/din_rail_adc/</guid>
      <description>One of our retrofit projects at work required using four small DAC boards to converet 0-5V PWM into true 0-10V analog voltage. I designed and printed some small snap-on DIN rail mounts for these to cleanly mount them in their enclosure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Airflow Passthrough</title>
      <link>http://example.org/oneoff/airpassthrough/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2021 13:17:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/oneoff/airpassthrough/</guid>
      <description>The airflow situation is often very stuffy, especially in the summer months. The adjacent workroom has abundant AC, enough to keep a full room full of incandescent fixtures at bay. I punched through the wall (with permission) and mounted the fan from an old server rack over the top. I added grills to both sides to prevent knicked fingers. I designed and 3d-printed a cover with locking knurled handles to cover the hole when I&amp;rsquo;m not present or the temperature is fine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analog Meter Class</title>
      <link>http://example.org/oneoff/meterclass/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 20:56:57 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/oneoff/meterclass/</guid>
      <description>On October 24th 2021, I taught an online streamed class on using Analog meters in electronics projects. It focused on the functionality of meters, figuring out how existing meters are set up and how to drive them, and how to create custom labels for existing meters.
&#39;&#39; </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Estate Sale (Oct &#39;21)</title>
      <link>http://example.org/oneoff/estatesale/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 20:56:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/oneoff/estatesale/</guid>
      <description>In October 2021, I attended the estate sale of a recently-passed Ham Radio operator (&amp;ldquo;silent key&amp;rdquo;). He had collected a wild variety of goodies over the years, a few of which caught my eye. I didn&amp;rsquo;t bring home nearly all of these, but I thought they were worth capturing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resistor Organization</title>
      <link>http://example.org/oneoff/resistororganization/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 20:56:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/oneoff/resistororganization/</guid>
      <description>In April 2016, I undertook to properly organize my E12 series resistors in a way that I could actually find the darn resistor I was looking for when I needed it. The result was many small, color-coded and labelled boxes that each contain a single value of resistor for easy access.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Votive Fence Hooks</title>
      <link>http://example.org/oneoff/weddinghooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 20:56:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/oneoff/weddinghooks/</guid>
      <description>I had very little to do with this one, but just think it&amp;rsquo;s neat - a friend was hosting a small backyard wedding, and while he had designed a 3D-printed hook to hold votive candles on a fence, his printer was down. I spun up around 30 hooks that week, and the wedding turned out beautiful.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
