<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Oneoffs on Jeff Glass</title>
    <link>https://jeff.glass/oneoff/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Oneoffs on Jeff Glass</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 10:16:14 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jeff.glass/oneoff/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Lighting Control Rack Overhaul</title>
      <link>https://jeff.glass/oneoff/lightingcloset/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 10:16:14 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeff.glass/oneoff/lightingcloset/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I tasked myself with overhauling one of the lighting control closets at work. This used to house a 1995 Unison Heritage lighting controller for archetectural control, as well as an MA2 remote playback unit to control some LED fixtures and moving lights. It was all housed in an abysmal rolling rack with no connectors on it; why the rack needed to roll is beyond me. I packaged it up into a freestanding rack and replaced the Unison Heritage processor with an ETC Nomad controller for proper entertainment lighting control; installed a new network switch; and fully documented the rack&amp;rsquo;s purpose, wiring, and configuration.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      &lt;
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KVM Stand</title>
      <link>https://jeff.glass/oneoff/kvm-stand/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 10:16:14 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeff.glass/oneoff/kvm-stand/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My work often involves switching between several computers - a laptop, a beefier desktop, an &amp;lsquo;IT Sanctioned&amp;rsquo; clean machine with access to the work network, and a temporary line to whatever computer&amp;rsquo;s on the workbench. To improve the ergonomics of using the KVM switch, I designed and 3D-printed a small stand to hold the switch controls, then labelled it using an old embossing Dymo label maker.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      &lt;
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virgin Receiver</title>
      <link>https://jeff.glass/oneoff/virgin-receiver/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 20:18:25 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeff.glass/oneoff/virgin-receiver/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the earliest homebrew ham radio transceivers I built was a direct-conversion receiver for the 40m band. I packaged it in the aluminum box of the &amp;ldquo;Lose Your Virginity&amp;rdquo; kit I had been given as a gag gift by some friends, and therefore christened it &amp;ldquo;The Virgin Receiver.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/fHS85k39iXo&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
      &lt;
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DIN Rail DAC Mount</title>
      <link>https://jeff.glass/oneoff/din_rail_adc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 12:47:53 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeff.glass/oneoff/din_rail_adc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of our retrofit projects at work required using four small DAC boards to converet 0-5V PWM into true 0-10V analog voltage. I designed and printed some small snap-on DIN rail mounts for these to cleanly mount them in their enclosure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      &lt;
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Airflow Passthrough</title>
      <link>https://jeff.glass/oneoff/airpassthrough/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2021 13:17:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeff.glass/oneoff/airpassthrough/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The airflow situation is often very stuffy, especially in the summer months. The adjacent workroom has abundant AC, enough to keep a full room full of incandescent fixtures at bay. I punched through the wall (with permission) and mounted the fan from an old server rack over the top. I added grills to both sides to prevent knicked fingers. I designed and 3d-printed a cover with locking knurled handles to cover the hole when I&amp;rsquo;m not present or the temperature is fine.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      &lt;
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analog Meter Class</title>
      <link>https://jeff.glass/oneoff/meterclass/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 20:56:57 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeff.glass/oneoff/meterclass/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On October 24th 2021, I taught an online streamed class on using Analog meters in electronics projects. It focused on the functionality of meters, figuring out how existing meters are set up and how to drive them, and how to create custom labels for existing meters.&lt;/p&gt;

 &#39;&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/r3Z6bVylrbs?autoplay=1&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; width: 50%; height: 50%;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video: Using Analog Meters in Electronics Projects&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#39; 
</description>
      &lt;
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Estate Sale (Oct &#39;21)</title>
      <link>https://jeff.glass/oneoff/estatesale/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 20:56:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeff.glass/oneoff/estatesale/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In October 2021, I attended the estate sale of a recently-passed Ham Radio operator (&amp;ldquo;silent key&amp;rdquo;). He had collected a wild variety of goodies over the years, a few of which caught my eye. I didn&amp;rsquo;t bring home nearly all of these, but I thought they were worth capturing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      &lt;
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resistor Organization</title>
      <link>https://jeff.glass/oneoff/resistororganization/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 20:56:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeff.glass/oneoff/resistororganization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In April 2016, I undertook to properly organize my E12 series resistors in a way that I could actually find the darn resistor I was looking for when I needed it. The result was many small, color-coded and labelled boxes that each contain a single value of resistor for easy access.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      &lt;
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Votive Fence Hooks</title>
      <link>https://jeff.glass/oneoff/weddinghooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 20:56:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeff.glass/oneoff/weddinghooks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had very little to do with this one, but just think it&amp;rsquo;s neat - a friend was hosting a small backyard wedding, and while he had designed a 3D-printed hook to hold votive candles on a fence, his printer was down. I spun up around 30 hooks that week, and the wedding turned out beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      &lt;
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ahab&#39;s Harpoon</title>
      <link>https://jeff.glass/oneoff/am-hpf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeff.glass/oneoff/am-hpf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For a production of Moby Dick, the director wanted Ahab&amp;rsquo;s harpoon to glow with a heated, unearthly light just before the second intermission. I glued some warm-white LED tape just below the plexiglass tines of the harpoon, and dimmed them with an &lt;a href=&#34;https://rc4wireless.com/&#34;&gt;RC4 Wireless Dimmer&lt;/a&gt;. The power came from three 18650 lithium ion batteries.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      &lt;
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AM Highpass Filter</title>
      <link>https://jeff.glass/oneoff/harpoon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeff.glass/oneoff/harpoon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I was getting started building amateur radios, I ran into an issue whenever I would go to operate by the lakefront in Chicago. The direct line-of-site to downtown meant my frontend was getting absolutely blasted through by the large AM transmitter sites downtown. I built a small (admittedly unshielded) high pass filter to cut off everything below about 3 MHz, and this helped some.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      &lt;
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>G3UUR Crystal Tester</title>
      <link>https://jeff.glass/oneoff/g3uur/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeff.glass/oneoff/g3uur/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When one is building a crystal filter for SSB reception in amateur radio, it&amp;rsquo;s critical to know some of the properties of the crystals one is using. Especially its exact resonant frequency, motional inductance and capacitance. THe &lt;a href=&#34;https://kk9jef.wordpress.com/2016/04/25/g3uur-crystal-oscillator/&#34;&gt;G3UUR Crystal Checker setup&lt;/a&gt; makes these relatively easy to determine, by switching an additional series capacitance in and out.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      &lt;
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home Radio Station</title>
      <link>https://jeff.glass/oneoff/radio-shack/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeff.glass/oneoff/radio-shack/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As part of my pursuits as a ham radio operator, I set about to install a humble ham radio station in preparation for the Winter of 2021-22. Prior to this, I had been limited to operating entirely portably, outdoors and away from the noise of the city. As the days grew colder, I added a couple of ELFA shelves underneath my 3D printer, to place my FT-891, antenna tuner, and a few other accessories. It works alright - there is indeed a lot of RF noise in the city. But it means I don&amp;rsquo;t have to wander out in to the cold just to play a little radio.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      &lt;
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homemade Bacon</title>
      <link>https://jeff.glass/oneoff/bacon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeff.glass/oneoff/bacon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During a summer sabatical, I experimented with making my own bacon. I obtained roughly 4 lbs of pork belly from a local butcher, wet-brined it for about a week in the fridge, then smoked half and oven-roasted the other half. The slow smoked was miles better, but I had more issues with heat-control, so some of the additional flavor was simply from caramalization on the outside.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      &lt;
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lighting XKeys</title>
      <link>https://jeff.glass/oneoff/ion-xkeys/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeff.glass/oneoff/ion-xkeys/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A very popular lighting controller in the theatrical nonprofit world is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.etcconnect.com/Products/Consoles/Eos-Family/Ion/Features.aspx&#34;&gt;ETC Ion&lt;/a&gt;, which was my primary controller two lighting jobs ago now. I found that a 16-key set of &lt;a href=&#34;https://xkeys.com/xk16.html&#34;&gt;Programming XKeys&lt;/a&gt; fits just right alongside the control console. The keys act like a USB keyboard to run pre-programmed macros on the console to replicate common or longwinded sequences of keystrokes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      &lt;
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robotics Competition</title>
      <link>https://jeff.glass/oneoff/robotics-comp-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeff.glass/oneoff/robotics-comp-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Spring 2016, I had the priveldge to MC a local middle school robotics competition that was part of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vexrobotics.com/v5/competition/vrc-current-game&#34;&gt;VEX Robotics Competition&lt;/a&gt;. The 2016 challenge, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=A8daR6qBw3M&#34;&gt;Nothing but Net&lt;/a&gt;, involved creating robots that behaved autonomously and then under remote control, to acquire and fling balls into nets. A true treat of a day, and some serious mechanical skill on the part of the middle-schoolers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      &lt;
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yorkshire Pudding</title>
      <link>https://jeff.glass/oneoff/yorkshire/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeff.glass/oneoff/yorkshire/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A traditional holiday dessert at my inlaws&#39; is Yorkshire Pudding. A simple egg and flour batter is poured into piping-hot muffin tins filled with melted butted and drippings from the holiday roast, which then rise and pop up into fluffy, delicious, buttery muffin things. Very tasty, would recommend.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      &lt;
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>