<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>radio on Jeff Glass</title>
    <link>https://jeff.glass/oneofftags/radio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in radio on Jeff Glass</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://jeff.glass/oneofftags/radio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>AM Highpass Filter</title>
      <link>https://jeff.glass/oneoff/harpoon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeff.glass/oneoff/harpoon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I was getting started building amateur radios, I ran into an issue whenever I would go to operate by the lakefront in Chicago. The direct line-of-site to downtown meant my frontend was getting absolutely blasted through by the large AM transmitter sites downtown. I built a small (admittedly unshielded) high pass filter to cut off everything below about 3 MHz, and this helped some.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      &lt;
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>G3UUR Crystal Tester</title>
      <link>https://jeff.glass/oneoff/g3uur/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeff.glass/oneoff/g3uur/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When one is building a crystal filter for SSB reception in amateur radio, it&amp;rsquo;s critical to know some of the properties of the crystals one is using. Especially its exact resonant frequency, motional inductance and capacitance. THe &lt;a href=&#34;https://kk9jef.wordpress.com/2016/04/25/g3uur-crystal-oscillator/&#34;&gt;G3UUR Crystal Checker setup&lt;/a&gt; makes these relatively easy to determine, by switching an additional series capacitance in and out.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      &lt;
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home Radio Station</title>
      <link>https://jeff.glass/oneoff/radio-shack/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeff.glass/oneoff/radio-shack/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As part of my pursuits as a ham radio operator, I set about to install a humble ham radio station in preparation for the Winter of 2021-22. Prior to this, I had been limited to operating entirely portably, outdoors and away from the noise of the city. As the days grew colder, I added a couple of ELFA shelves underneath my 3D printer, to place my FT-891, antenna tuner, and a few other accessories. It works alright - there is indeed a lot of RF noise in the city. But it means I don&amp;rsquo;t have to wander out in to the cold just to play a little radio.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      &lt;
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>