<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Jeff Glass</title>
    <link>https://jeff.glass/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Jeff Glass</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 11:39:55 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jeff.glass/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Demilight</title>
      <link>https://jeff.glass/project/demilight-is-a-very-small-3d-printed-moving-light/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 11:39:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeff.glass/project/demilight-is-a-very-small-3d-printed-moving-light/</guid>
      <description>The Demilight project began in 2019 with the goal of creating a 3D printable, miniature moving light controlled by an Arduino-compatible microcontroller. This page catalogs the current state of the project, along with project history and assembly instructions.
Currently, the project is on Version 0.9.4.
There are still enough rough-edges that the project that I haven&#39;t published the STLs for the 3D-printed parts, nor the gerbers/BOM for the controller. I don&#39;t intend to try to reach perfection before releasing everything, I just want to get rid of some of the more egregious &#39;gotchas&#39; so someone who&#39;s not me stands a good chance of building one successfully.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LoRa-DMX Wireless LED Controller</title>
      <link>https://jeff.glass/project/wirelessly-triggering-on-costume-led-pixel-effects/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 10:00:22 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeff.glass/project/wirelessly-triggering-on-costume-led-pixel-effects/</guid>
      <description>In the late summer of 2021, I was contracted to implement a remotely-triggered Pixel LED controller for a client. They were looking to create some interesting effects on jumpsuits worn by performers, using LED Pixel-Tape attached to the suits.
A handful of key contraints for this project were:
There weren&#39;t enough DMX addresses available from the lighting controller to do per-pixel control straight from the lighting desk. However:The effects still wanted to be controllable in some way from the lighting desk.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
